A Guide to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company Records, 1836-1943
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company Records, 1836-1943
The Library of Virginia
4364, 30428
196 maps, 67 plans, 25 charts and 16 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Chessie System (Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company), Huntington, West Virginia, April-July 1977, June 1978.
Biographical Information
The Louisa Railroad Company, incorporated in 1835, merged, on Feb. 18, 1836, with the Virginia Central Railroad Company. On Aug. 31, 1868, the Covington and Ohio Railroad Company and the Virginia Central Railroad Company merged to form the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company. In 1870 the Blue Ridge Railroad Company merged into the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company which, in 1878, was reorganized as the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.
Scope and Content
Records, 1836-1943, of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company mainly consist of maps of the James River and vicinity formerly occupied by the James River and Kanawha Canal. The railroad bed was laid on the canal towpath, and many maps show the relative positions of the canal and the railroad right of way. The collection also consists of letters and proposals concerning construction or alterations affecting the property of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.
There are 196 maps cataloged by location, with a date range from 1836 to 1943. One map is a later compilation of surveys dating back to 1825. The 67 plans are also arranged and listed by location and cover the years 1848 to 1927. The 25 charts and graphs range from 1870 to 1927. The additional 16 records cover the years 1886, 1892, 1895 and 1898.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Maps, 1836-1943
Series II. Plans, 1848-1927
Series III. Charts, 1870-1927
Series IV. Records, 1886-1898
Contents List
- Series I. Maps, 1836-1943., Extent: 196 maps.
  The maps relate to a variety of subjects. While most show railroad rights of way along the old canal, others contain surveys of routes through towns, such as Charlottesville, Lynchburg, Richmond, and Hampton; plats of railroad depots and private property condemned for the use of the railroad; and surveys of branch line routes.
  - Map of the various Routes of a Rail-Road between Covington and the Ohio River, 1870., Dimensions: 38 x 92 in.; Scale: 2 miles to 1 in.; Media: Backed with linen. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 750 R15 1870 (1))
  - Map of various Routes of a Rail-Road between Covington and the Ohio River, 1870., Dimensions: 41 x 88 in.; Scale: 2 miles to 1 in.; Media: Backed with linen. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 750 R15 1870 (2))
  - Map of Chesapeake and Ohio R.R. 1870., Dimensions: 41 x 203 in.; Scale: 2 miles to 1 in.; Media: Backed with linen. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 750 R15 1870 (3))
  - Falls Branch, Maryland. Surveyed under the direction of S.F. Baird, U.S. Commissioner of Fisheries, to determine the location of the Great Falls Fishway. Designed by Marshall McDonald. n.d.., Dimensions: 26 x 18 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 752 H9 n.d.)
  - Proposed transfer track at Charleston, W. Va. Chief Engineer's Office, C. & O. Ry. April 1886., Dimensions: 16.5 x 33 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754.37 S8 1886)
  - [Map of part of Charleston, West Virginia, showing routes of tracks of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad and the Kanawha and Ohio Railroad. See also 754.37 S8 [1886] (1)]. 1886., Dimensions: 17 x 38 in.; Scale: 450 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754.37 S8 [1886])
  - [Map of part of Charleston, West Virginia, showing routes of tracks of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad and the Kanawha and Ohio Railroad. Enlarged portion of 754.37 S8 [1886]]. 1886., Dimensions: 18.5 x 30 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754.37 S8 [1886] (1))
  - Map showing condemnation limits for Roadway and Depot purposes [St. Alban's Station, Kanawha County, W. Va.]. n.d.., Dimensions: 16 x 30 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754.37 S8 n.d.)
  - [Map showing railroad right of way through property of Henry and Stephen Rigg along New River in Fayette County, West Virginia]. n.d.., Dimensions: 11 x 13.5 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754.71 S8 n.d.)
  - Profile and alignment Notes of the Iron Mt. & Greenbrier R.R. from White Sulphur to Forks [of] Anthony Creek [Greenbrier County]. By A.D. Williams, Ast. Engr. November 25, 1902., Dimensions: each 8.5 x 29 in., pts. 1 and 2 8.5 x 24 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Blueprint.; Sheets: 9. (Othertype 754.88 R15 1902)
  - Map of Resurvey of Iron Mountain and Greenbrier Railroad. A.D. Williams, Engineer, Marlinton, W. Va. October 18, 1905., Dimensions: each 30.5 x 20.5 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueprint.; Sheets: 12. (Othertype 754.88 R15 1905)
  - [Plat showing lands needed for use of Covington and Ohio Railroad in Greenbrier County, beginning at Alleghany County line]. 1859?., Dimensions: each 15.5 x 19.5 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 754.88 S8 1859?)
  - Ashford General Hospital. White Sulphur Springs, W. Va. Property Survey. January 1943., Dimensions: Copy 1, 27 x 20 in. Copy 2, each 27 x 20 in.; Scale: 1000 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Copy 1 positive reversed blueline maps. Copy 2 negative photostat (reversed writing).; Sheets: Copy 1, 1. Copy 2, 2. (Othertype 754.88 S8 1943 copy 1, copy 2)
  - [Map showing lands condemned for canal from Daniel's Island (Campbell County) to Pattonsburg (Botetourt County]. 1825-1882., Dimensions: 15 x 27 in.; Scale: Scales differ. Most are 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored. Bound.; Sheets: 121. (Othertype 755 C2 ca. 1882)
  - Profile, J.R. & K. Canal, coppied [sic] from Map in office of A.C. & I. Co. [Shows profile from Richmond to Greenbrier River]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 15 x 30 in.; Scale: Horizontal, 5 m. to 1 in. Vertical, 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755 C2 n.d.)
  - Profile Canal from Mile 141 to Clifton Forge. n.d.., Dimensions: Parts 1 and 2, 11 x 21.5 in. Parts 3 and 4, 11 x 29 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript profile. Colored.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755 C2 n.d. (1))
  - Maps of the First Grand Division of the James River and Kanawha Canal [Richmond to Lynchburg] Accompanied by a M[ap] of the Dock a[t] Richmond. Surveyed & drawn by C. Radziminsky. n.d.., Dimensions: each 23 x 35 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript maps. Colored.; Sheets: 114. (Othertype 755 C2 n.d. (2))
  - Property maps of the Richmond and Alleghany R.R. Richmond to Clifton Forge including the Buckingham R.R. and the Lexington Branch. 1886., Dimensions: each 21.5 x 31 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript maps on linen paper.; Sheets: 273. (Othertype 755 R15 1886)
  - Profile, Southern Railway, Monroe [Amherst County] to Danville [Pittsylvania County]. R.F. Ezzell, Res. Engr. F.O. Duenner, A.E. Jan. 23, 1902., Dimensions: each 22 x 29 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Blueprint profile.; Sheets: 34. (Othertype 755 R15 1902)
  - [Map showing route of railroad from Fort Monroe, Hampton, to Richmond, Henrico County]. ca. 1907., Dimensions: each 9 x 16 in.; Scale: 500 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 64. (Othertype 755 R15 ca. 1907)
  - Fencing charts, eastern division, C. & O. Ry. Co. n.d.., Dimensions: 19 x 24 in.; Scale: Horizontal, 300 ft. to 1 in. Sections, 60 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript charts. Colored. Bound.; Sheets: 105. (Othertype 755 R15 n.d. (1))
  - [Plat of right of way from Richmond to Hampton]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 12 x 36 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 64 (nubmers 1 and 2 missing). (Othertype 755 S8 1886)
  - [Right of way map, Richmond to Clifton Forge]. 1905?., Dimensions: each 20 x 34 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 191 (sheets 1-4, 119, 145, 146 missing). (Othertype 755 S8 1905?)
  - Plat of Co's Property, Gordonsville. Plat of Land of Va. Midland Ry. Co. at Gordonsville, Va. From W.M.S. Dunn, Engr. & Supt. April 9, 1884., Dimensions: 10 x 17.5 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.381 S8 1884)
  - Hampton Branch, C. & O. Railway. Land Maps. 1882., Dimensions: each 15.5 x 25.5 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript maps. Colored.; Sheets: 16. (Othertype 755.411 S8 1882)
  - Plan of Williamsburg from a Map taken in 1803. n.d.., Dimensions: 33 x 28 in.; Scale: 10 poles to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.4159 1803 n.d.)
  - Grade Profile, Richmond to Mechum's River [Albemarle County]. Made in 1853-4 by order of the Board of Public Works. 1853-1854., Dimensions: 18 x 25 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript profile. Bound.; Sheets: 13. (Othertype 755.42 R15 1853 1854)
  - Map of Air Line [railroad] from Richmond to Charlottesville. Made by S. A. Richardson. [Internal evidence indicates that this map was made after 1855.] February 1855., Dimensions: each 27 x 19 in.; Scale: 4000 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map.; Sheets: 5. (Othertype 755.42 R15 1855 n.d.)
  - R. & A. R. R. East from Lynchburg. Sheets [33] 37 to 53. n.d.., Dimensions: each 23.5 x 18 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 36. (Othertype 755.42 R15 n.d.)
  - [Map showing route of railroad from Lindsay Station, Albemarle County, to Upper Bremo, Fluvanna County]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 9 x 16 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 29. (Othertype 755.42 R15 n.d.)
  - General Plan of Wharves. Richmond, Va., n.d.., Dimensions: 24 x 60 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.42 R15 n.d. (2))
  - Map Showing Plan of Wharfage for C. & O. R. R. on James River near Richmond. n.d.., Dimensions: 32.5 x 69 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Backed with linen. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.42 R15 n.d. (3))
  - Map of a part of Richmond City, Va., showing lines run for extension of C. & O. R. R. to James River. n.d.., Dimensions: 38 x 61 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Backed with linen. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.42 R15 n.d. (4))
  - [Right of way map from Henrico County through Albemarle County]. Piedmond [sic] Division. Richmond to Clifton Forge. n.d.., Dimensions: each 25 x 38 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 117 (numbers 1 and 2 missing). (Othertype 755.42 S8 n.d.)
  - Map of the Upper Section of the Lower Level of the James River and Kanawha Canal. Surveyed by Joseph J. Pleasants. January 24th, 1868., Dimensions: 21 x 15 in. and 21 x 25 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1868)
  - Map of the Upper Section of the Lower Level of the James River and Kanawha Canal. Surveyed by Joseph J. Pleasants. Copied Nov. 1, 1880. January 24, 1868., Dimensions: each 21 x 23 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1868 1880)
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 456.00-506.00, incl. M. P. 8.6 to 9.2 Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 20.5 x 26 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936)
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 27.00 to 506.00, inc. M. P. 0.5 to 9.2. Henrico County, Virginia. November 4, 1936.., Dimensions: each 21 x 28 in.; Scale: Horizontal, 1000 ft. to 1 in. Vertical, 2 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (1))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 27.00 to 286.00, incl. M. P. 0.5 to 5.4. Henrico County, Virginia. September 19, 1936., Dimensions: each 20 x 24 in.; Scale: Horizontal 100 ft. to 1 in. Vertical, 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (2))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 88.00-l62.00, incl. M. P. 1.7 to 3.1. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 20 x 25 in.; Scale: 10ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (3))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 244.15-281.85, incl. M. P. 4.6 to 5.3. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 25 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (4))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 165.88-198.00, incl. M. P. 3.1 to 3.7. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 25 in.; Scale: Scales differ.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (5))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal Between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 244.15-281.85, incl. M. P. 4.6 to 5.3. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 25 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (6))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 200.00-243.20, incl. M. P. 3.7 to 4.6. Henrico County, Virginia. September 17, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 25 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (7))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 315.00-358.00, incl. M. P. 5.9 to 6.8. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 25 in.; Scale: Scales differ.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (8))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 360.80-451.50, incl. M. P. 6.8-8.6. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 22.5 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (9))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 27.00-87.00, incl. M. P. 0.5 to 1.7. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 25 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (10))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 286.00-506.00, incl. M. P. 5.4 to 9.2. Henrico County, Virginia. September 19, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 23-1/2 in.; Scale: Horizontal, 100 ft. to 1 in. Vertical, 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (11))
  - Cross Sections and Profiles of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Tredegar and Bosher's Dam. Stations 281.96-312.00, incl. M. P. 5.3 to 5.9. Henrico County, Virginia. September 18, 1936., Dimensions: each 21 x 20.5 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.43 C2 1936 (12))
  - [Map of railroad right of way, Henrico County]. 1880., Dimensions: each 13 x 31 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.43 R15 1880)
  - [Map showing parts of lots condemned for railroad right of way]. Henrico Co. 188l?., Dimensions: 11 x 16.5 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.43 S8 1881?)
  - [Map of James River and Kanawha Company's Richmond dock property between 14th Street and Ash Street]. Surveyed by Joseph J. Pleasants. December 15, 1866., Dimensions: each 28 x 20 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1866)
  - [Map of James River and Kanawha Company's Richmond dock property between 14th Street and Ash Street]. Surveyed by Joseph J. Pleasants. Nov. 30, 1866., Dimensions: 24 x 33 and 24 x 36.5 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1866 1880)
  - Map of the Lower Section of the Lower Level of the James River and Kanawha Canal, with its connection with the Dock. Surveyed by Joseph J. Pleasants. Drawn by M. Bates. March 14, 1868., Dimensions: each 27 x 18 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1868)
  - Map of the Lower Section of the Lower Level of the James River [and] Kanawha Canal with its connection with the dock. Surveyed by Joseph J. Pleasants, March 14th, 1868. Copied Dec. 1, 1880. Dec. 1, 1880., Dimensions: each 30 x 19 .in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1868 1880)
  - [First sheet of map of James River and Kanawha Canal, Richmond to Clifton Forge. This sheet shows canal and city from Ash Street to 7th Street]. 1890?., Dimensions: each 21 x 21 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1890?)
  - C & 0 Railroad. Map and profile of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal. Richmond, Va. Vicinity of Gallego Mills. October 16,1926., Dimensions: each 10.5 x 17.5 in.; Scale: 1/4 mile to 1 in.; Media: Two sets. Blueprint and profile.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1926)
  - Cross Sections of the James River and Kanawha Canal between Gallego Mills and Haxall [Henrico County]. January 23, 1939., Dimensions: each 22 x 28.5 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline Print.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 C2 1939)
  - Map of the Richmond and Manchester Water Power Canals. n.d.., Dimensions: 21 x 40-1/2 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 C2 n.d.)
  - 3 Mile Locks [Richmond, Virginia]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 19.5 x 26.5 in.; Scale: 20 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 C2 n.d. (1))
  - Sketch of James River at Richmond (Plan for improving Water Power submitted by R. Shirreffs). July 19, 1892., Dimensions: 16 x 8 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Blueprint.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 H9 1892)
  - Map of James River at Richmond showing Improvement of Water Power. Proposed by Reuben Shirreffs, Civ. & Hyd. Eng'r. Dec. 1892., Dimensions: each 17 x 27.5 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueprint.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 H9 1892 (1))
  - [Profile of James River bottom around Belle Isle near Richmond]. n.d.., Dimensions: 11 x 41 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript profile.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 H9 n.d.)
  - Map of locality. Eight and Canal Streets. Richmond, Va. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Enlarged from Joseph J. Pleasants' Map of March 14th, 1868. Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in. n.d.., Dimensions: 12 x 30.5 in.; Scale: 20 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1868 n.d.)
  - Map of the Ship-Lock Basin [Richmond Dock]. Survey under the direction of R. H. Temple, Temple, Chief Engineer, R. & A. R. R. Co. By C. P. E. Burgwyn, A. B., C. E. May 1881. Soundings taken Aug. 1, 1892. Oct. 17, 1899., Dimensions: each 22.5 x 18 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map.; Sheets: 5. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1881 1892 & 1899)
  - Map of C. & O. R'y Cos. Lot at Comer of 7th & Canal Streets, Richmond, Va., showing also the portion of S. S. Web1ett's Lot occupied by Side Track and colored green. F. B. Isaacs, Asst. Engr. July 21, 1892., Dimensions: 22 x 17 and 22 x 15 in.; Scale: 20 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1892)
  - Location of Proposed Bulkhead near New Grain Elevator, 10th Str., Richmond, Va. F. B. Isaaacs, Asst. Engr. July 1893., Dimensions: 19 x 21 in.; Scale: 20 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1893)
  - Partial map of Second Street Yard, C. & 0. Ry. Co., Richmond, Va. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Oct. 14, 1893., Dimensions: each 24 x 20 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1893 (1))
  - Map showing 8th Street Yard & Vicinity. Richmond, Va. Oct. 1894., Dimensions: each 20 x 28 in.; Scale: 40 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1894)
  - Vicinity of Ninth and Cana1 Sts., Richmond, Va. F. B. Isaacs, De1r. June 1894., Dimensions: 15 x 36 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1894 (1))
  - Map of Eighth Street between Cary & Canal Streets. Richmond, Va. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Nov. 5th, 1895., Dimensions: 12 x 32.5 in.; Scale: 20 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1895)
  - Map of Property in the City of Richmond, Va., on the west side of Eighth Street between Cary and Canal Streets showing frontages of the same on 8th Street, names of owners, and the position and dimensions of the Foot-Bridge over the Tracks of the Chesapeake & Ohio Rail Road at that point. Also side view and end view of the Bridge. James T. Redd & Son. Aug. 2, 1895., Dimensions: 17.5 x 24.5 in.; Scale: Map, 20 ft. to 1 in. Bridge plan, 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueprint.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1895 (1))
  - Sketch Map (compiled from other maps not from surveys) showing Proposed locations of Richmond Passenger Depot on Broad Str. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Sept. 1898., Dimensions: each 29.5 x 18 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1898)
  - Sketch Map (compiled from other maps not from surveys) showing Proposed location of Richmond Passenger Depot on Broad Str. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Oct. 1898., Dimensions: each 29 x 18 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1898 (1))
  - Map of the Richmond Dock & Vicinity. Richmond, Va. Surveyed by A. E. Coulter. Drawn by F. B. Isaacs. October 1899., Dimensions: 8 x 21.5 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1899)
  - Map of the Richmond Dock & Vicinity. Richmond, Va. Surveyed by A. E. Coulter. Drawn by F. B. Isaacs. October 1899., Dimensions: 18 x 24 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript preliminary map.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1899 (1))
  - Sketch Map (compiled from Richmond Viaduct & Terminal Maps) Showing Proposed location of Richmond Passenger Depot on South side of Broad Str. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Feb'y 1899., Dimensions: each 29 x 18 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1899 (2))
  - Sketch Map (compiled from Richmond Viaduct & Terminal Maps) showing Proposed location of Richmond Passenger Depot on North Side of Broad Str. F. B. Isaacs, A. E. Feb'y 1899., Dimensions: each 29.5 x 18.5 in.; Scale: 50 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1899 (3))
  - Richmond Dock & Vicinity from 13th Street to Ship locks. F. B. Isaacs, Engr. W. P. May 1901., Dimensions: each 28.5 x 21 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 R15 1901)